DOUGLAS BOBERG

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I authored the profitable and patented PostureScreen iOS app. My experience in both tech and leadership has given me an assortment of hard and soft skills. Having worked in startup and established environments, I have achieved a track record of delivering successful mobile apps, web products, and systems integration software.

STRENGTHS

- Results driven
- Full stack developer
- Innovative and relentless problem solver
- Effective and efficient communicator
- Emotionally intelligent yet no-nonsense team leader
- Active and accountable Product Owner
- Thrive in collaborative, fast-paced environments

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

- Co-inventor on US Patent 11,017,547 B2 and patent-pending CA 3,042,819 A1
- Proven Objective-C and Swift iOS developer
- Java, Dropwizard, Jetty, Jersey, Jackson web server, and microservices
- Kotlin and Java Android developer
- AWS Beanstalk, S3, and Docker deployments
- MS SQL, MySQL, and DynamoDB
- Adobe Certified Expert in Advanced ColdFusion
- Standard 'baseline' technologies: JavaScript, git, bash, ssh, JSON, XML, jQuery, CSS, HTML, JIRA

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

PostureCo

Trinity, Florida

Wright Flood

St. Petersburg, Florida

Ikonetics

St. Petersburg, Florida

Adrena

St. Petersburg, Florida

Jagged Peak, Inc.

Tampa, Florida

SnapDragon Medical, Inc.

Clearwater, Florida

Nextweb Media

Plantation, Florida

Freya Communications

Ft. Lauderdale, Florida

FDN Communications

Maitland, Florida

DSM.net

Lakeland, Florida

Chief Software Developer, CTO, Owner

December 2015 - Present

Development Manager & Trainer

June 2012 - December 2016

President, Owner

April 1998 - Present

Chief Technical Officer, Owner

October 2010 - April 2013

Team Lead & Software Engineer

July 2006 - July 2010

Principal Engineer

July 2008 - September 2008

Senior Programmer

February 2006 - July 2006

Senior Programmer

November 2005 - February 2006

Senior Programmer

March 2004 - November 2005

3D Animator & Lead Programmer

February 1997 - April 1998

EXPERIENCE

PostureCo

Chief Software Developer, Owner

Trinity, Florida

December 2015 - Present

I developed and currently maintain the PostureScreen iPad, iPhone, and Android mobile apps. PostureScreen was featured in Money, DETAILS, and GQ Australia magazines and is frequently in the "Top 25" App Store rankings of paid iPad Health & Fitness apps.

As part of the Development team, I write Swift and Objective-C software for new prototypes and existing consumer applications. Our solutions include Apple Augmented Reality, AWS, and Google Cloud components.

Utilizing a small team to implement ambitious projects requires hands-on collaboration, which is perfect for my work style. While successfully mentoring the technology team, I am also directly involved in the design and building of marketable solutions.

As part of the Executive team, I am responsible for the company's strategic technology decisions.

We frequently examine new markets, and I bring technical solutions that help us expand into those markets. I identify and research technology that aligns with our long-term strategies.

I introduced highly successful software development lifecycle processes encompassing quality assurance, defect ticketing, and continuous integration systems.

Wright Flood

Development Manager & Trainer

St. Petersburg, Florida

June 2012 - December 2016

Identified technology projects for investigation, design, and implementation. Frequently met with executive-level management on development project progress.

Spearheaded technology advancements for the company by identifying projects for research, design, and implementation. Provided hands-on engineering and prototyping with team mentoring to ensure successful project results.

Provided personal research to Wright Flood, revealing an opportunity for a cost-saving, in-house solution. Built a successful proof-of-concept application for senior management review.

Provided one-on-one training to developers for ColdFusion, Java, bug tracking, and source control tools. Managed technical support personnel and implemented bug-reporting processes.

Ikonetics

President, Owner

St. Petersburg, Florida

Apri 1998 - December 2015

Created the patented "PostureScreen" iPad/iPhone application that uses the camera and accelerometer to calculate posture displacement and export the result as a PDF report.

Created the "Flood Zone Maps" Android and iPad application using FEMA/NFIP data sources to display insurance risk information for the United States.

Created assorted utility and leisure apps for other clients; "Gowalla Sniffer", "Everyday Genealogy", "Woot Alerts", "Go Go Lotto", and "Virtual Vine".

Trained engineers and architects from The Walt Disney Company, City of Port St. Lucie, and RS&H Architects critical aspects of 3d modeling and animation.

Modeled and animated Clearwater Florida's Memorial Causeway bridge for HDR Engineering. The marketing team used the animation during city council meetings to demonstrate the bridge's impact on the community.

Adrena

Chief Technical Officer, Owner

St. Petersburg, Florida

October 2010 - April 2013

Founded a new venture to offer LexisNexis comprehensive investigative data to law enforcement.

Used ColdFusion to create the "IDPursuit" case management site, including web service APIs for data integration with TLO, LexisNexis, OpenCNAM, and others.

Designed and configured the entire server network using Linux, Apache/Tomcat, and MySQL database servers.

Jagged Peak, Inc.

Team Lead & Software Engineer

Tampa, Florida

July 2006 - July 2010

Managed and mentored a small team of junior developers in ColdFusion, SQL, and JavaScript. Encouraged best practices and assisted with problem-solving.

Architected, documented, and implemented ColdFusion-based integration across Web Services and FTP, using both XML and EDI formats, with an MS SQL backend.

Presented technology recommendations directly to Executive staff during daily and weekly planning meetings.

Responsible for maintaining legacy ColdFusion order management system, content management system, custom business applications, e-commerce websites, and API.

Worked on-site with client to install custom Flash, ColdFusion, and MS SQL gaming systems, and transitioned code base to client's developers.

SnapDragon Medical, Inc.

Principal Engineer

Clearwater, Florida

July 2008 - September 2008

Updated and maintained HIPAA-compliant subscription website using Java, XWork, and MySQL.

Nextweb Media

Senior Programmer

Plantation, Florida

February 2006 - July 2006

Led the development team in creating a ColdFusion and MS SQL-based billing integration system.

Freya Communications

Senior Programmer

Ft. Lauderdale, Florida

November 2005 - February 2006

Programmed a combined ColdFusion and ASP custom Digital Rights Management (DRM) solution for video distribution.

FDN Communications

Senior Programmer

Maitland, Florida

March 2004 - November 2005

Designed and implemented a ColdFusion and MS SQL-based XML Web Service API, allowing wholesale vendors access to custom internal systems.

DSM.net

3D Animator & Lead Programmer

Lakeland, Florida

February 1997 - April 1998

Wrote custom Perl scripts to provide interactive data mining and reporting for client websites and Intranet applications.

Used 3D Studio Max to model and animate a 3D orange grove visual for a Florida Orange Growers commercial. The commercial aired nationally during the Florida Orange Bowl.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science

Columbia College

Art

1996

Courses in 3d Studio, Softimage, Photoshop, and traditional classes included Painting, Life Drawing, Photography, and Art History.

Associate of Applied Science

Monroe Community College

Drafting

1994

Engineering classes using CAD and traditional drafting and design.